Arrington Dixon Papers 132
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Arrington Dixon Papers
1935-2008
1953-1989
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Dixon, Arrington
132
17 Boxes
9.5 Linear feet
Arrangement
The collection is divided into four series: Series 1: Campaigns Series 2: City Government Series 3: Personal Series 4: Photographs
Biographical / Historical
Arrington Dixon is a local politician who served on the District of Columbia City Council as a Representative of Ward 4, Chairman, and an At-Large Member. Dixon was born in Washington, DC on December 3, 1942. He attended Birney Elementary, Douglass Junior High School, and McKinley Technical High School where he participated in the Cadet Corps program. Dixon went on to attend college at Howard University where he studied economic statistics, math, and physics; and participated in the Air Force ROTC. He transferred to the Air Force Academy for a short time, but returned to Howard following the 1964 death of his brother James W. Dixon, Jr., who served in the United States Air Force. After his graduation in 1966, Dixon worked for various institutions as a computer/systems analyst and educator. He ran for the Ward 5 Board of Education seat in 1968, which he ultimately lost. In 1972, Dixon earned a law degree from George Washington University. He ran for the then-newly established DC City Council in 1974, serving as Ward 4 Representative from 1975 to 1979, City Council Chairman from 1979 to 1982, and later for a brief period of time as an At-Large Member in 1997. Dixon was also involved with the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission and a number of other community groups such as the Metropolitan Washington Council of Governments, the National Capital Planning Commission, and DC Citizens for Better Public Education. Dixon married future District of Columbia Mayor Sharon Pratt (Kelly) in 1966. Their marriage ended in 1982. Dixon and Kelly have two children, Aimee and Drew. Since serving as an elected official, Dixon founded Arrington Dixon and Associates, Inc. (ADAI) a professional consulting and public liaison service.
Custodial History
Arrington Dixon donated this collection to the DC Public Library's Special Collections Department in August 2013.
Related Materials
Related Collections: Collection 029: Hilda Mason Papers Collection 131: Charlene Drew Jarvis Papers Collection 002: District of Columbia Citizens for Better Public Education Records
Scope and Contents
The Arrington Dixon Papers Collection contains materials including campaign ephemera; correspondence; newspaper clippings and publications; photographs; pamphlets; and other documents related to Dixon's political campaigns, work in city government (especially for the District of Columbia City Council), and personal life. The bulk of the collection covers 1953 to 1989.
Politics and government; Politicians; District of Columbia. City Council; Political campaigns; Transportation; Personal and Family Papers; Photographs; Ephemera; Correspondence; African Americans
- Series 1: Campaigns, 1974-1982; 7 Boxes
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains items such as candidate questionnaires, voter surveys, fundraising and budget materials, meeting agendas and notes, schedules, ephemera (bumper stickers, pamphlets, flyers, buttons, advertisements, etc.), correspondence, press releases, and newspaper clippings related to Arrington Dixon's political campaigns when he ran for the District of Columbia City Council. This series is divided into five (5) sub-series: Sub-Series 1: Outreach, Events, and Planning, Sub-Series 2: Fundraising and Financials; Sub-Series 3: Campaign Ephemera; Sub-Series 4: Publications; and Sub-Series 5: Correspondence.
  - Subseries 1: Outreach, Events, and Planning, 1974-1982; 4 Boxes
    This sub-series contains candidate questionnaires, voter surveys, meeting agendas and notes, event flyers and programs, schedules, and speeches and statements pertaining to Arrington Dixon's political campaigns, especially through voter outreach, planning, and strategy.
    - Advance Manual for the Evelyn E. Murphy Campaign, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Candidate Questionnaires, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Candidate Questionnaires, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Comprehensive Planning Document: Arrington Dixon, Chairman, DC City Council, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Planning Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Schedules, September 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Schedules, August 1982 (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Schedules, August 1982 (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Schedules, July 1982 (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Schedules, July 1982 (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Schedules, May and June 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Schedules, March and April 1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Schedules and Events, 1968-1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Event Flyers and Programs, 1974-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Speeches and Statements, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Statements and Speeches, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Survey of Voter Attitudes and Opinions, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Voter Surveys, 1978-1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Appendix C: Tabulations, Vol. 1, DC Voters Survey, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - The Get-Out-The-Vote Master Action Plan, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Campaign Strategy and Planning Documents, 1978-1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Campaign Strategy and Planning Documents, 1976-1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Memorandum Related to Campaign Planning, 1975-1982 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Arrington Dixon Campaign Committee and Groups, 1974-1982 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Position Summaries, 1974-1982 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Volunteer Materials, 1974-1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Volunteer Materials (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Handwritten Notes and Contacts (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Notecards with Constituent Contact Information (Box 16)
  - Subseries 2: Fundraising and Financials, 1974-1982; 2 Boxes
    This sub-series contains fundraising, budgeting, and financial materials related to Arrignton Dixon's political campaigns.
    - Budgeting, Expenses, and Quotes, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Budgeting, Expenses, and Quotes, 1978-1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Fundraising Events, 1978-1982 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Contributor Forms, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Fundraising Contributions, 1974-1982 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 3: Campaign Ephemera, 1974-1982; 2 Boxes
    This sub-series contains campaign advertisements, campaign literature, bumper stickers, buttons, flyers, and voter guides from Arrington Dixon's political campaigns, as well as some items from other candidates' campaigns.
    - TV and Radio Advertisements, 1978-1982 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Campaign Literature, 1978-1982 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Printed Campaign Advertisements, 1976-1982 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Printed Campaign Advertisements (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Printed Campaign Advertisements (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Campaign Literature and Advertisements, Other Candidates, 1974-1978 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Sample Ballots and Voter Guides, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Bumper Stickers and Buttons (Box 17)
  - Subseries 4: Publications, 1974-1982; 1 Boxes
    This sub-series contains press releases, newsletters, and newspaper clippings related to Arrington Dixon's political campaigns.
    - Press Releases, Newsletters, and Newspaper Clippings, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Press Releases, Newsletters, and Newspaper Clippings, 1974-1981 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 5: Correspondence, 1974-1982; 1 Boxes
    This sub-series contains correspondence pertaining to Arrington Dixon's political campaigns, including some letters related to campaign fundraising contributions.
    - Campaign Correspondence, March 1978 - September 1982, 1978-1982 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Campaign Correspondence, March 1974 - April 1977, 1974-1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Series 2: City Government, 1963-1989; 8 Boxes
  This series contains items such as budget materials, speeches, statements, information about bills and legislation, invitations, correspondence, event programs and materials, newsletters, newspaper clippings, and press releases related to Arrington Dixon's time spent serving on the District of Columbia City Council and the DC Taxicab Commission. This series is divided into five (5) sub-series: Sub-Series 1: Financials, Sub-Series 2: Speeches and Actions; Sub-Series 3: Calendar and Events, Sub-Series 4: Publications, and 5 Correspondence.
  - Subseries 1: Financials, 1979; 3 Boxes
    This sub-series contains Arrington Dixon's copies of the Budget of the District of Columbia for FY1977 - FY1980.
    - The Budget of the District of Columbia FY80, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - The Budget of the District of Columbia FY79 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - The Budget of the District of Columbia FY78 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - The Budget of the District of Columbia FY77 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - District of Columbia Capital Projects Financing; Critical Analysis of a New Approach, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 2; Speeches and Actions, 1975-1989; 2 Boxes
    This sub-series contains speeches, statements, and information about bills and legislation from Arrington Dixon's time spent serving on the District of Columbia City Council and the DC Taxicab Commission.
    - DC Taxicab Commission, 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - No Fault Motor Vehicle Insurance Bill, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Speeches and Statements, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Speeches and Statements, 1975-1980 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Update and Inquiry Procedures for the Dixon Constituency File, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Legislation Introduced by Councilmember Arrington Dixon (1 of 3), 1977 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Legislation Introduced by Councilmember Arrington Dixon (2 of 3), 1977 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Legislation Introduced by Councilmember Arrington Dixon (3 of 3), 1977 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Bills, 1975-1979 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 3: Calendar and Events, 1975-1989; 2 Boxes
    This sub-series contains invitations, correspondence, and event programs and materials from Arrington Dixon's time spent serving on the District of Columbia City Council.
    - Democratic National Convention, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Inauguration Activities, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Inauguration Activities, 1974-1977 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Event Programs and Materials, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Thank You Letters and Drawings from La Salle Elementary School Students, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - April and May 1976 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - DC City Council Calendar, March 1976 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - DC City Council Calendar, February 1976 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - DC City Council Calendar, January 1976 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - DC City Council Calendar, December 1975 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - DC City Council Calendar, November 1975 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - DC City Council Calendar, October 1975 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - DC City Council Calendar, September 1975 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - DC City Council Calendar, August 1975 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - DC City Council Calendar, July 1975 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - DC City Council Calendar, June 1975 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - DC City Council Calendar, May 1975 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - DC City Council Calendar, April 1975 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - DC City Council Calendar, March 1975 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - DC City Council Calendar, February 1975 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Democratic National Convention Bag (Box 17)
  - Subseries 4: Publications, 1963-1989; 2 Boxes
    This sub-series contains newsletters, articles, newspaper clippings, press releases, and other publications related to Arrington Dixon, the District of Columbia City Council, and the DC Taxicab Commission.
    - District of Columbia Taxicab Commission Newspaper Clippings, 1987-1989 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - District of Columbia Taxicab Commission News Clippings, June 25, 1987 - March 18, 1988 by David M. Watson, Public Information Officer, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - DC City Council Press Releases, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Council of the District of Columbia Owner's Manual, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Arrington Dixon Newspaper Clippings, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - DC City Council/Arrington Dixon Newspaper Clippings, 1980-1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - DC City Council/Arrington Dixon Newspaper Clippings, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - DC City Council/Arrington Dixon Newspaper Clippings, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - DC City Council/Arrington Dixon Newspaper Clippings, 1963-1977 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Newsletters and Articles, 1978-1981 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 5: Correspondence, 1968-1978; 3 Boxes
    This sub-series contains cards, letters, and copies of correspondence from Arrington Dixon's time serving on the District of Columbia City Council.
    - DC City Council Correspondence, 1978-1982 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, December 1977 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, November 1977 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, October 1977 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, September 1977 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, July and August 1977 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, June 1977 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, May 1977 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, April 1977 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, December 1976 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, November 1976 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, October 1976 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, September 1976 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, August 1976 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, July 1976 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, June 1976 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, May 1976 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, April 1976 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, October 1975 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, September 1975 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, August 1975 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, July 1975 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, June 1975 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, May 1975 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, April 1975 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, March 1975 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, February 1975 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - DC City Council Correspondence, January 1975 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Cards and Correspondence, 1968-1978 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Series 3: Personal, 1935-2008; 3 Boxes
  This series contains programs, awards, correspondence, official documents, newspaper clippings, certificates, notes, and drawings related to Arrington Dixon's personal life, especially with regard to his education, professional life, and family. Series 3 is divided into three sub-series: Sub-Series 1: School, Work, and Church, Sub-Series 2: Family, and Sub-Series 3: Miscellaneous Items, and Sub-Series 4: Photographs.
  - Subseries 1: School, Work, and Church, 1957-2008; 1 Boxes
    This sub-series contains programs, awards, certificates, correspondence, and various other items related to Arrington Dixon's accomplishments and activities through school, work, and church.
    - A Visit Through History: DC Council Photos, 2008 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Ten Years of Home Rule, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - District of Columbia Federation of Civic Associations Thirty Eighth Annual Awards Dinner, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Copyright Certificates and Information, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Awards and Certificates, 1966-1987 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Employment Paperwork and Identification Cards, 1966-1968 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Commencement Exercises Programs, 1955-1966 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1959-1968 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - High School and Church Activities, 1957-1960 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Arrington L. Dixon Resume (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Howard University (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 2: Family, 1935-1990; 2 Boxes
    This series contains correspondence, official documents, programs, newspaper clippings, certificates, some genealogical research, and other items related to members of Arrington Dixon's family, especially his father and mother (James W. Dixon, Sr. and Sallie Dixon) and brother (James W. Dixon, Jr.), who died while serving in the United States Air Force.
    - American Indian Ancestry Research, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - James W. (Sr.) and Sallie Dixon, 1954-1963 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - James W. (Sr.) and Sallie Dixon, Cards and Correspondence, 1935-1967 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - James W. Dixon, Sr., Funeral Service, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - James W. Dixon, Sr., Golf, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - James W. Dixon, Jr.'s Death; Insurance, Benefits, and Communication with U.S. Air Force, 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - James W. Dixon, Jr.'s Death, Funeral and Obituaries, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - James W. Dixon, Jr., Newspaper Clippings, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - James W. Dixon, Jr., U.S. Air Force, 1961-1963 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - James W. Dixon, Jr., Correspondence, 1957-1964 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - James W. Dixon, Jr.; School, Work, and Church, 1953-1962 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - James W. Dixon, Jr., Awards and Certificates, 1953-1961 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Sharon Pratt, Correspondence, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Dorothy Frances Arrington and Julian Raymond Davis, Wedding Invitation, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 3: Miscellaneous Items, 1953-1989; 3 Boxes
    This sub-series contains miscellaneous notes, drawings, and items whose owner is unclear.
    - Congressional Record, Vol. 135, No. 98, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Guest Books, 1979-1982 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Drawings, 1964-1989 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Church Programs and Pamphlets, 1953-1964 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Greeting Cards (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - List of Addresses (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - License Plate (Box 17)
- Series 4: Photographs, 1976-1987; 3 Boxes
  This series contains images (photographs, contact sheets, and negatives) of Arrington Dixon, Dixon's time campaigning and serving on the District of Columbia City Council, and the Dixon family.
  - Arrington Dixon Portrait Photographs, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Arrington Dixon Portrait Contact Sheets (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Campaign and DC City Council Photographs, 1976-1981 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Campaign and DC City Council Photographs (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Campaign and DC City Council Contact Sheets, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Personal and Family Photographs, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Personal and Family Contact Sheets (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Oversized Photographs, Contact Sheets, and Negatives (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Arrington Dixon Portrait Negatives (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Arrington Dixon Portrait Negatives (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Arrington Dixon Portrait Negatives (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Campaign and DC City Council Negatives (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Campaign and DC City Council Negatives (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Campaign and DC City Council Negatives (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Campaign and DC City Council Negatives (Box 15, Folder 7)